So, how do you tell the quality of tea?
The quality of tea comes from different places.
The leaf, the type of leafs, what it looks like before it's brewed, what it looks like after it's been brewed.
Also, the aroma of the tea leaves before you brew it.
If it smells, if there is no scent that the tea leaves impart before it touches water, it might be a tea that's been on the counter or on sale for a bit long.
You want to get a tea that imparts a certain aroma.
And if you get, once you've smelled it you want to brew the leaf, and once you brew the tea leaf, and the aroma from the cup has to be stronger or impart something similar of the dry leaf brew, but much stronger.
And the other thing is the to look at the clarity of the color of the brew.
If you get a a longjing or dragon well, which is a very popular Chinese green tea, the brew will be very clear.
If it's cloudy, it means you've got dust in the tea leaves and it also might be old.
And the flavor of the tea should be very present; even if you're drinking a white tea that you think is a very mild tea, so you shouldn't really taste the tea.
But the sweetness of the white tea will come out when it's fresh and if it's a good quality tea.
Thank you.